<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Curiosity on murmuring in the background</title>
    <link>/categories/curiosity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Curiosity on murmuring in the background</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/curiosity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>my reaction to _Hidden Figures_</title>
      <link>/2019/10/11/hidden-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/11/hidden-figures/</guid>
      <description>I’m a bit overwhelmed and a bit sick this month, and i didn’t want to miss two fortnights in a row. I wrote up this reaction to seeing the film Hidden Figures a couple of years ago on Facebook, and several of my friends liked it then, so i’m sharing it here. It’s slightly edited. –Cory
Hidden Figures was probably the best civil rights–focused film i’ve seen in a while—not to disparage Selma or The Butler, but my personal taste is for greater subtlety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>embed with the Petersens</title>
      <link>/2019/03/01/embeddability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/01/embeddability/</guid>
      <description>inreach I make a habit of responding when people reach out for mathematical support in their work, at least when i think i can contribute something. An interesting network effect of this habit is that i actually get more second-hand (i.e. forwarded) feelers from colleagues than first-hand requests. As a result, i’ve gotten exposure to a lot of disciplines and questions that i’d’ve otherwise been unaware of entirely, for example the problem of feature identification in the immune profiles of cancer patients and the statistical bookkeeping required to model the nested factors determining medical imaging phenotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>