<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methodology on murmuring in the background</title>
    <link>/categories/methodology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Methodology on murmuring in the background</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/methodology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>the mapper construction in base R</title>
      <link>/2020/05/01/mapper-construction-base-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/01/mapper-construction-base-r/</guid>
      <description>Several mature, open-source implementations of the mapper construction now exist, including the standalone Python Mapper module and KeplerMapper, part of the scikit family. I’m currently experimenting with Matt Piekenbrock’s R package Mapper, which is not on CRAN but makes—from my beginner’s vantage point—exemplary use of the R6 system.1
What these implementations have in common is that the underlying construction is mostly hidden from view. Users can specify its constituent parts, but what gets visualized is almost exclusively either</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to calculate aesthetics in a ggplot2 extension</title>
      <link>/2020/04/17/calculate-aesthetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/17/calculate-aesthetics/</guid>
      <description>how to use computed variables One of the many subtle features of ggplot2 is the ability to pass variables to aesthetics that are not present in the data but rather are computed internally by a statistical transformation (stat). For users, the documentation for this feature illustrates the use of stat(&amp;lt;variable&amp;gt;) (previously ..&amp;lt;variable&amp;gt;.., since upgraded to after_stat(&amp;lt;variable&amp;gt;)) in an aesthetic specification.
Some stats do this by default. For example, the count stat sends its computed count to both coordinate aesthetics by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>comparable pairwise and multivariate associations from presence-absence data</title>
      <link>/2019/08/30/presence-absence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/30/presence-absence/</guid>
      <description>A project i’ve had in the works for years, and “almost done” since last summer, is a sensitivity and robustness analysis of several techniques used in studies of “comorbidity networks” (also “disease graphs”, “disease maps”, etc.) that have appeared over the past 20 years. As i begin the abstract:
 Comorbidity network analysis (CNA) is an increasingly popular approach in systems medicine, in which mathematical graphs encode epidemiological correlations (links) between diseases (nodes) inferred from their occurrence in an underlying patient population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>multidimensional scaling of variables, and rank correlations</title>
      <link>/2019/08/16/rank-correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/16/rank-correlations/</guid>
      <description>A fundamental idea in biplot methodology is the conference of inertia, a phrase i picked up from an SO answer by ttnphns and quickly incorporated into ordr. The basic idea arises from the central properties of a biplot, illustrated here for principal components analysis: A case–variable data matrix \(X\in\mathbb{R}^{n\times m}\) of ratio variables1 is singular-value decomposed as \(X=UDV^\top\), for example the mtcars data set:
x &amp;lt;- scale(mtcars, center = TRUE, scale = TRUE) s &amp;lt;- svd(x) r &amp;lt;- length(s$d) Under this convention, \(U\in\mathbb{R}^{n\times r}\) and \(V\in\mathbb{R}^{m\times r}\) arise from eigendecompositions of \(XX^\top\) and of \(X^\top X\), respectively, and \(D\in\mathbb{R}^{r\times r}\) is the diagonal matrix of the square roots of their (common) eigenvalues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling uniformly from an embedded Klein bottle</title>
      <link>/2019/02/01/sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/01/sampling/</guid>
      <description>an apparent dearth of toy TDA samplers Experimenting and practicing with topological data analytic (TDA) tools requires a healthy diversity of suitable data sets. Several real-world classics can be found in various packages, for example the glucose and insulin test data collected and analyzed by Reaven and Miller and later used by Singh, Carlsson, and Mémoli to illustrate the Mapper construction, which is included in the heplots package:
data(Diabetes, package = &amp;quot;heplots&amp;quot;) head(Diabetes) ## relwt glufast glutest instest sspg group ## 1 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>